A Guide to the Evans-Sibert family Papers, 1800-1928
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Evans-Sibert family Papers, 1800-1928
Library of Virginia
27770
.70 cubic feet
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Deposited by E.B. Steele, Richmond, Va., 30 June 1972.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Evans and Sibert families were from Frederick and Shenandoah Counties, but settled in Augusta County, Virginia. Lorenzo Sibert, born 1810, founded the Siberton Steel and Iron Company of Augusta County, Virginia. David H. Evans, born 1841, of Staunton, Virginia, married Mary Anna Sibert Evans, born 1842, in 1869. David H. Evans family lived in Winchester, Virginia, where they ran a tobacco store.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1800-1928, of the Evans and Sibert families of Augusta, Frederick, and Shenandoah Counties, and Winchester, Virginia. Includes correspondence, receipts, insurance policies, patents, deeds, stock certificates, circulars, and land surveys.
Includes correspondence, 1863-1890, of David H. Evans, mainly concerning family and business. Includes many letters written to Mary Sibert Evans, during their courtship and after their marriage; an amnesty oath, dated 11 July 1865; and an insurance policy from the Royal Society of Good Fellows, 30 March 1887. Includes report cards of Lorenzo Evans from Staunton public schools, tax receipts, and correspondence, and correspondence and receipts for W.R. Evans, 1897-1899. Lorenzo and W.R. Evans were the children of David and Mary Evans.
The papers of Joseph L. Sibert, include a patent, drawing, and specifications for a machine for forging Spencer rifle cartridge cases, granted by the Confederate States of America, 1865. The papers of Lorenzo Sibert, 1856-1881, include correspondence, patents, agreements, receipts, leases, and an oath to the Confederate States of America, 5 August 1862. Most of the papers relate to the mining and furnace inventions of Lorenzo Sibert. Included are land leases, 1869-1881, to mine ore in Augusta and Page Counties, Virginia. Also includes a list of wages due to mine laborers; stock certificates for the Sibert-Patent Iron and Steel Company, 1870; and a land survey for Siberton Steel and Iron Company.
Also included in the papers is a copy of a rally song for the University of Virginia; circular for the sale of land to be used for mining in Albemarle County, Virginia; a comical circular commenting on the raid of John Brown, written in Charlestown, 30 November 1859; theatre circular for a Louisville Dramatic Club performance, 21 December 1860; Circular No.1 issued by R. D. Lilley, regarding the arrest of deserters and absentees in the Confederate Army, 22 March 1865; G.W. Gail and Ax price list for tobacco, 13 August 1887; the publication, The Wishing Cap, by Mrs. Sherwood; a prohibition ticket for the election in Augusta County, Virginia, 1887 November 8; and Republican election tickets for the election of James A. Garfield, 2 November 1880.
Contents List
- David H. Evans, Correspondence, 1863-1867 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- David H. Evans, Correspondence, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- David H. Evans, Correspondence, 1869-1883 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- David H. Evans, Correspondence, 1887-1890 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- David H. Evans, Papers, 1865-1887 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Lorenzo Evans, Papers, 1880-1901 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Mary Anna Sibert Evans, Correspondence, 1859-1861 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Mary Anna Sibert Evans, Correspondence, 1862-1867 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Mary Anna Sibert Evans, Correspondence, 1868-1869 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mary Anna Sibert Evans, Correspondence, 1870-1888 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mary Anna Sibert Evans, Correspondence, 1889-1897 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mary Anna Sibert Evans, Papers, 1859-1896 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- W. R. Evans, Papers, 1897-1899 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Lorenzo Sibert, Correspondence, 1856-1881 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Mrs. Lorenzo Sibert, Correspondence, 1861-1880 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1861-1900 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Joseph L. Sibert, Papers, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Lorenzo Sibert, Papers, 1837-1877 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Lorenzo Sibert, Patents and papers relating to mining, 1870-1881 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous, 1800-1928 (Box 2, Folder 4)